<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<RulesCondition xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<RC>
		<Code>C0618</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF 'Requested procedure code' = '71' THEN this data group / data element can not be used ELSE it is Required.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>C0619</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested Procedure Code = '71'  THEN this data item can not be used ELSE it is Optional.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>C0638</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF this data item different to D.E. '3/18 - declarant identification No.' 
THEN it is REQUIRED 
ELSE it can NOT BE USED</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>C0646</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF first digit of 'Inland transport mode' = '5' or '7'
THEN the 'Identification number' AND 'Type of identification' cannot be used
ELSE the 'Identification number' AND 'Type of identification' = 'R'</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0010</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF ‘Type of packages (code)’ indicates ‘BULK’ (UNECE rec 21 : ‘VQ’, ‘VG’, ‘VL’, ‘VY’,’VR’,'VS' or ‘VO’)
THEN ‘Number of packages’ can not be used
ELSE ‘Number of packages’= ‘R’</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0016</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF TraderOfficeCode is Empty or ID is Finnish personal identification number
THEN 'Name' and 'ADDRESS' must be used,
ELSE 'Name' and 'ADDRESS' must not be used.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0021</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF 
 - Requested procedure is customs warehouse (71),
 - Requested procedure is end use (44), outward processing (46, 48), inward processing (51) or temporary admission (53) and additional information code 00100 is not used,
 - additional declaration type is C, F, Y, U, Z or V
THEN Authorisation is REQUIRED
ELSE IF Dataset type is H5N
        THEN Authorisation is NOT USED	
        ELSE OPTIONAL.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0022</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure = 71,
  then if (previous procedure is 00 and declaration type is CO) or (goods location is in [FI994400, FI994900, FI998002, FI999500, FI999800, FI999801])
            then previous document is optional
            else previous document is required
  else ( -&gt; requested procedure different then 71)
          if (declaration type is IM, country of departure is NO and transport mode at border is 3)
          then previous document is optional
          else previous document is required
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0025_OPT</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If specified by the relevant 'Additional information code
THEN this data element is REQUIRED
ELSE it can NOT be USED</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0027</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF ((Declaration is lodged by private person)
      AND (Mode of transport at the border is mail (5)
THEN Trader reference number (LRN) is OPTIONAL 
ELSE it is REQUIRED</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0028</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Previous Document Type is = 337 or 355 THEN data element is Required</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0030</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H2 or warehouse is declared then this is not used,
else this is required.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0031</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Declaration is lodged by private person,
THEN
    data element is OPTIONAL
ELSE //C0010
    IF (first digit of ‘Mode of Transport at the border’ = ‘2’, ‘5’ or ‘7’) OR (Additional procedure = 615)
    THEN ‘Nationality of active means of transport crossing the border ’ can not be used
    ELSE ‘Nationality of active means of transport crossing the border ’ is Required</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0035</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Type of location is B or C,  Economic operator (function "EO") can be used
else
cannot be used</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0036</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Type of location = C,  function="Authorisation" can be used
ELSE
function="Authorisation"  cannot be used</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0037</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Type of location is  is A, C or D, location "Address" can be used
ELSE
If Type of location = B , Location "Address"  cannot be used</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0038</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Dataset type is H2, I2 or Mean of transport at the border is 3
then Customs Office can be used (optional),
else cannot be used</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0039</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional information code FITAK is used, credit direct representative (status code 2) must be declared.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0101</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H7,
then this is required, 
else it is used.
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0103</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H7,
then this is optional,
else it is not used.
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0108</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Declaration is lodged by private person (Declarant or (both Declarant and representative))
THEN 
      data item is NOT REQUIRED 
ELSE 
     IF TraderOfficeCode is Empty 
     THEN data item is REQUIRED
     ELSE cannot be used</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0109</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional declaration type is X or Y, MRN is required,
else if additional declaration type is Z, MRN is optional (depending if exists I2 notification),
else not used.
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0110</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is lodged retrospectively (additional declaration type is R),
then Elected entry is required.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0200</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF H5 or I1
THEN data item can NOT be USED
ELSE data item is REQUIRED</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0202</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H1, then this is required,
else if dataset type is H3, H4 or H5E, then this is optional,
else not used.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0203</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Dataset type = H2 then this is required, else optional</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0204</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Additional procedure = 615
THEN data item is OPTIONAL
ELSE data item can NOT be USED</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0205</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF dataset is H1 or H5
THEN data item is OPTIONAL
ELSE data item can NOT be USED</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0206</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Not used for H2, H5, I1, else required</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0207</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H3, H4 or H5 then this is not used,
else optional.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0208</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Not used for H2, H5N, I1, else required (or as other conditions apply)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0209</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Additional procedure = 615
THEN data item can NOT be USED
ELSE data item is REQUIRED</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0210</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Not used for H5N, optional for other datasets</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0211</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N, then this is not used,
else if dataset type is I1 and requested procedure is different than 42 or 63, then this is optional,
else this is required.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0212</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Not used for H2 and H5 National, required for all the other datasets (or as other conditions apply)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0213</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Optional for H1, not used for all the other datasets, e.g. H2, H5, ...</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0214</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF  Additional procedure = 615
THEN data item is OPTIONAL
ELSE data item is REQUIRED</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0216</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF I1 or H5N, THEN cannot be used, ELSE = R</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0217B</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF (H5 FI) or H2
THEN data item can NOT be USED
ELSE
    IF H5 EU and declaration lodged by private person
    THEN OPTIONAL
    ELSE REQUIRED</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0218</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N or H7, then CN code is not used,
else if dataset type is H2, then CN code is optional,
else if dataset type is H1 or H5E, CN code is required (unless NC0223 applies).</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0219</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N, H2 or I1, then this is not used,
else required.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0220</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF TraderOfficeCode does not exists 
THEN data item is REQUIRED 
ELSE cannot be used
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0221</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF IdentificationNumber exists
THEN the element is OPTIONAL
ELSE it can NOT be USED
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0222</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF H5 (EU or FI)
THEN data group can NOT be USED
ELSE REQUIRED</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0223</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N then this is not used,
else if (dataset type is H1 or H7, declaration is lodged by private person (importer + representative) and additional procedure C08 is used) OR (dataset type is H5E)
       then this is optional,
       else it is required.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0224</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If invoice on header level exists, also Currency unit must be used. Otherwise it is not used.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0226</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF H2
THEN data item can NOT be USED
ELSE this data group / data element is REQUIRED </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0227</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Dataset type is H2, H3, H4 or H5 (both E/N) then not used,
else if (requested procedure is 42 or 63) or (additional procedure F48 is used)
       then required,
       else it is optional.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0228</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is 71,
then this is optional,
else it is required.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0229</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF the declaration is lodged by private person
THEN
        IF exists Additional procedure code C08, B02, B03
        THEN
                NationalAdditionalCode ("Q" code) is OPTIONAL
        ELSE
     	THEN NationalAdditionalCode ("Q" code) is REQUIRED (it should be declare at least one of them)
ELSE (declarant is a company)
       IF Importer is Municipality, Association/Non-Profit or Government,
       THEN 
	NationalAdditionalCode ("Q" code) is OPTIONAL
       ELSE
	IF importer is not VAT registered, 
       	THEN
                	NationalAdditionalCode ("Q" code) are REQUIRED
      	 ELSE
		NationalAdditionalCode ("Q" code) is OPTIONAL
      	ENDIF
        ENDIF
ENDIF</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0230</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N or H7, then Taric code is not used,
else if dataset type is H2 or H5E, then Taric code is optional,
else if dataset type is H1, Taric code is required (unless NC0223 applies).</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0231</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If
 - dataset type is I2 and additional information code FIPER is used, or
 - additional declaration type is C or F and additional information code FIPER is used, or
 - additional declaration type is U or V
then this is required. 
If dataset type is H2, then this is not used,
Optional for other cases (or as other conditions imply).</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0233</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF dataset type is not H1 and declaration is lodged retrospectively (additional declaration type is R)
THEN this data group/element is optional, else it is required (or as other conditions suggest).</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0234</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Declaration is lodged retrospectively (additional declaration type is R)
THEN this data group/element is not used, else required (or as other conditions suggest)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0235</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If preferential code indicating quota [x20, x25, x28] THEN Quota order number = R, ELSE cannot be used.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0236</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Preference code starts with 2,3,4 then Country of preferential origin required, else optional</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0237</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration dataset is H1 or H7, additional procedure code F48 is used and valid IOSS number of vendor is given in Additional fiscal trader reference group with role FR5,
then VAT rate code (NationalAdditionalCode beginning with Q) is optional, else as other conditions (NC0229) apply.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0238</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5 (both H5N and H5E), or H7 (low value consignment) and additional procedure F49 is used, representative must exist</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0239</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional information code FISUR is provided, DutyTaxFee/ElectedEntry must be declared</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0240</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>New implementation based on UTUK-1391 referring UTU Internal User Interface Specification Part 2, page:

IF FI414/Invalidation/FreeFormInvalidationReason = D
THEN
          ReplacingMRN is Required
ELSE
      IF FI414/Invalidation/FreeFormInvalidationReason = V
       THEN
          ReplacingMRN is Optional
       ELSE 
          ReplacingMRN is NotUsed</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0241</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If reason for invalidation is U, V, E or K, then reason text is mandatory; else it is optional.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0242</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF (Declaration is lodged by private person AND inland mode of transport = 5 (mail)
THEN this data group / data element (Trader reference number) is OPTIONAL
ELSE it is REQUIRED
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0243</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF (Declaration is lodged by private person)
THEN data item cannot be used
ELSE required

//Definition for private person will change - Importer or both Importer and Representative</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0245</Code>
		<DescriptionEn> IF Condition=XXX(Other), then LocationName = R</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0246</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If the goods are packaged together in such a way that it is impossible to determine the gross mass of the individual items, then gross mass is entered on declaration level. -&gt; If Total gross mass exists on header level, then cannot be used on goods items level, else must be used on each goods items</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0248</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code FIAJE exists (indicating split declaration), DutyTaxFee/ElectedEntry must be declared</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0249</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is lodged by private person, buyer cannot be declared.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0250</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N or I1, then this is not used,
else optional (or as other conditions imply).</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0251</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N or H2, then this is not used,
else if dataset type is I1, then this is optional,
else this is required.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0252</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H3 (without additional procedure D51)  or H4, then this is not used,
else this is optional.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0253</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is I1, H2, H3 or H5, then this is not used,
else this is optional.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0254</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Declaration is lodged retrospectively (additional declaration type is R)
THEN this data group/element is optional, else it is required (or as other conditions suggest).</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0256</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H1 or I1, then this is optional (or as other conditions imply),
else this cannot be used.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0257</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional declaration type is U or V with notification (CLE previous document exists), then this is optional.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0258</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional declaration type is (X, Y, U) or (V or Z with I2 notification), then this is not used.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0259</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is 51 or 53, then this is not used,
else required.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0260</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional declaration type is  U, then this is required,
else if additional declaration type is V, then this is conditional (NR1014),
else this is not used.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0261</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N, then this is not used,
else if dataset type is H2 or (H5E lodged by private person), then this is optional,
else this is required.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0300</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N
then if importer is not VAT-registered then this is required, if importer is VAT registered this is not used.
Optional (or as other rules and conditions apply) for other datasets.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0301</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N and importer is VAT-registered then this is required, else optional or as other conditions apply</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0302</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N then not used, else optional</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0303</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N and importer is VAT-registered then this is optional, for VAT not registered it is not used. 
For other datasets optional or as other conditions apply</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0304</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N then this is required, else optional</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0305</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>H5N: ElectedEntry (VAT Period date) is required for H5N</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0329</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If previous document type is 355 or 337 from UTU Entry, then data element is Required</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0350</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If repayment method is cash then not used, else required.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0353</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If repayment method is IBAN and the account is from SEPA area then required, else not used</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0357</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Required for cash, non-IBAN or IBAN non-SEPA payments, else not used</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0360</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If request is sent by the trader and amendment type is PAL, repayment information must be given</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0361</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If amendment type is KOR (before release of goods), reason code, text, payment details nor attachments cannot be provided.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC0362</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>This detail is mandatory for an amendment request after release</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NC1254</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Amount in supplementary measure unitis is required by TARIC codelist</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NPR0003</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>UTU must fetch trader details (of declarant, representative etc.), if a trader office code has not been declared and a country code in the trader identification number is not FI. Trader needs not necessarily be found.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NPR0005</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If trader is found from Trader Register (or EOS) and is EORI registered, then name and address will be overwritten if provided</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0001</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If authorisation type is CWP and requested procedure = 71, authorisation holder id and the identification number of the declarant must be the same</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0002</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure = 71 and representation status is 3 (indirect representation) then authorisation type must be CW1 or CW2 (authorisation type CWP for private warehouse is not allowed)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0005</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure = 71 and additional procedure is F31, previous procedure must be 21</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0006</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure = 71 and additional procedure is F32, previous procedure must be 51</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0007</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure = 71 and additional procedure is F34, previous procedure must be 44</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0008</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is standard customs declaration (FI415) and previous procedure is 21,
then if case is customs warehousing declarations (requested procedure 71), previous document type must be type one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952, ZZZ,
        else the  previous document type must be one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952, ZZZ or 781.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0009</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF previous procedure is 44 and there is at least one Requested procedure = 71 (Customs warehouse)
THEN
	previous document MUST be declared with type 'IM' (national previous document type) 
	AND as reference is case identification number of end use declaration (and import must be found from other customs clearance system)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0010</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is standard customs declaration (FI415) and previous procedure is 51m
then previous document type must be one of IM, 821 or ZZZ.
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0011</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is standard customs declaration (FI415) and requested procedure is 40, 42, 61, 63 or 71,
then if commodity code starts with 8701 - 8705, additional information code FIXBC (and vehicle identification number (VIN) / chassis number as a value for it) must be declared.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0019</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If location address has been declared, country code must be FI </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0020</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>All goods items must have the same value</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0021</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If previous procedure is 71
THEN
	there MUST be declared one of the following previous documents:
	- type ZZZ and reference to customs warehousing SAD
	- type MRN and customs warehousing MRN (in UTU)
	- type 821 and transit MRN</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0022</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is standard customs declaration (FI415) with previous procedure is 00 or low value consignment (FI485),
then if case is customs warehousing declarations (requested procedure 71), previous document type must be type one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952, ZZZ,
        else the  previous document type must be one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952, ZZZ or 781.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0023</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requested procedure = 71 then if authorisation type is CW1 then warehouse type must be R
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0023_b</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requesetd procedure = 71 then if authorisation type is CW2 then warehouse type must be S</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0024</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure = 71 then if authorisation type is CWP then warehouse type must be U</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0025</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If authorisation type is CW2, authorisation holder id and the identification number of the declarant must be different</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0026</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>In case the value of 'Number of Packages' is ‘0’ then there should exist at least one goods item with the same 'Shipping marks' and 'Type of packages', and 'Number of Packages' with value greater than ‘0’</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0027</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is 71, there must be one of the following authorisation types (3/39): CWP, CW1, CW2</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0028</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>It is not allowed to declare the same authorisation type more than once</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0029</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>There must not be more than one declared customs warehousing authorisation (CWP, CW1 or CW2)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0030</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>There must be exactly one GoodsShipment.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0032</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Must be greater than zero</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0034</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Must start with a two digit country code (EU or non-EU - CL008)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0035</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If the format of the trader id is FI + 9 characters, then modulus validation of Finnish EORI id must be performed. Format must be 'FI' + 7 digits + hyphen + check sum digit</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0036</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If the format of the trader id is FI + 11 characters, then modulus validation of Finnish personal identification number must be performed.


 Format must be

 'FI' + 6 digits + hyphen

 or

 'A' + 3 digits + check sum character</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0044</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Atleast one of notification text, or provided information must be present.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0045</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Atleast one of Description, document link must be present.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0046</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Additional declaration type cannot be amended</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0047</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Representative ID cannot be amended</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0049</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Service provider has to be differnet from importer, declarant and representative.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0049_I2</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Service provider has to be differnet from declarant and representative</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0052</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If hearing response is negative (disagree), at least one of notification text, or provided information must be present.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0055</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration type is CO, then country of dispatch/export must be an EU country.
If declaration type is IM, then country of dispatch/export must not be an EU country.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0056</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Representative must be a Finnish company or a Finnish private person</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0057</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If representative is a private person, then declarant and importer must be a private person as well.
If representative does not exist and declarant is a private person, then importer must be a private person as well.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0060</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is standard customs declaration (FI415) and previous procedure is 53,
then if previous document type must be one of IM, 821 or ZZZ.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0061</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is standard customs declaration (FI415) and previous procedure is 10,
then if case is customs warehousing declarations (requested procedure 71), previous document type must be type one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952, ZZZ,
        else the  previous document type must be one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952, ZZZ or 781.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0062</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is standard customs declaration (FI415) and previous procedure is 22,
then if case is customs warehousing declarations (requested procedure 71), previous document type must be type one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952, ZZZ,
        else the  previous document type must be one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952, ZZZ or 781.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0063</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is standard customs declaration (FI415) and previous procedure is 23,
then if case is customs warehousing declarations (requested procedure 71), previous document type must be type one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952, ZZZ,
        else the  previous document type must be one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952, ZZZ or 781.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0064</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is standard customs declaration (FI415) and previous procedure is 54,
then the previous document type must be one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952 or ZZZ.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0065</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is standard customs declaration (FI415) and previous procedure is 78,
then the previous document type must be one of 337, 355, 820, 821, 952 or ZZZ.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0066</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If previous procedure is 71 (customs warehousing), then location type code must be B - authorised place.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0068</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>All previous documents in the declaration must be from the same procedure group
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0069</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is 42 or 63, then Identification number must a Finnish EORI</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0070</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>When previous procedure is 53, there must be declared additional information code 00900; else it cannot be declared.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0071</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>When previous procedure is 51, there must be declared additional information code 00700; else it cannot be declared.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0100</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Combination of requested, previous and additional procedure must be correct according to the codelist.	</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0101</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If case is supplementary declaration (additional declaration type U, V, X, Y, Z) and this data element or group was already declared on simplified declaration/EIDR notification, it cannot change. 
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0102</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If case is 1..1 supplementary declaration (additional declaration type X, Y or Z with notification) and this data element or group was already declared on simplified declaration/EIDR notification, it cannot change. </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0103</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If case is recapitulative supplementary declaration (additional declaration type U or V with notification), then all simplified declarations must be lodged in the same period.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0104</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Simplified declaration in question must be in state released (sub state Waiting for supplementary) and there cannot exist any unresolved change request.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0105</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional declaration type is U, then this must be case with additional declaration type C or F and with additional information code FIPER.
If additional declaration type is V, then this must be EIDR presentation notification.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0110</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Case identification (/Identification) of incoming request must be unique in the declaration. </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0111</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Case identification (/Identification) of incoming request must be unique</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0201</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5FI, additional declaration type must be A or R</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0202</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Either UN/LOCODE for the location or the country code as provided for D.E. 3/1 Exporter followed by the name of the location is required</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0203</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested Procedure is = 42 or 63 THEN this value must be FR2
ELSE If Addtl. procedure code F48 exists on all goods items, THEN this value must be FR5</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0210</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>NationalAdditionalCode, if used, must exist in Arvonlisa codelist</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0220</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5EU, additional declaration type must be A, D or R</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0224</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is lodged under procedure 42 or 63,
the trader declared under Additional Fiscal Trader Reference cannot be finnish - must not begin with "FI"</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0225</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>For retrospectively lodged cases (additional declaration type R), ElectedEntry must be in the past and maximally three years in the past for declarations lodged by the trader (EXT UI/DME/TUTTU), or maximally five years in the past for declarations lodged by Customs (INT UI).
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0226</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>For H5N, ElectedEntry must be maximum 30 days (one month) in the past, today or maximum 30 days (one month) in the future.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0227</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>For split declarations (additional information code FIJAE used), ElectedEntry must be maximum one year in the past or today.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0228</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional declaration type is U, V or (C or F with additional information code FIPER), then
- if period is week ("W"), then elected entry must be the Monday of this week,
- if period is month ("M"), then elected entry must be the first day of this month.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0229</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional information code FISUR is used, ElectedEntry must be maximum 3 years in the past or today.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0230</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>AdditionalInformation / Description string can be converted to Decimal value</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0231</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is lodged by private person, requested procedure must be 40, 61 or 71.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0232</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is lodged by private person, previous procedure must be 00, 21 and 71.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0234</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Either Economic Operator, Authorization number, Customs Office or Address must be used in goods location.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0235</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional information code FITAK is used, credit direct representative (status code 2) must be declared.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0236</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is different than 71 and representation status is 2 (direct) or 1 (self - no representative is used), then declarant identification number and importer identification number must be the same.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0237</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If transaction channel is message exhange, requested procedure is different than 71 and representation status is either 1 (self representation/no representative exists) or 2 (standard direct representation without code FITAK),
then declarant must be a credit trader.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0238</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If transaction channel is message exchange, requested procedure is different than 71 and representation status is either 2 with additional code FITAK (direct representative providing the guarantee) or 3 (indirect representative),
then representative must be a credit trader.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0239</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H7, only VAT codes (starting with "Q") can be used</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0240</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is postal (mode of transport = 5) and additional declaration type is D, previous document must be 355.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0241</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5 (both H5N and H5E) or H7 (low value consignment) and additional procedure F49 is used, direct FITAK representative with credit trader status must exist.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0242</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Specific tax base quantity unit must be upper case string [A-Z0-9]*.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0243</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF dataset is H7
THEN Additional Declaration type must be A, R or D.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0245</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional declaration type is C, F, Y or U, 
then there must exists authorisation with type SDE.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0246</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional declaration type is Z or V,
then there must exists authorisation with type EIR.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0249</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is 44, 46 or 48,
then additional information code FIPER cannot be used.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0250</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional declaration type is X, Y or U, then this must be SDE,
else if additional declaration type is V or Z, then this must be CLE.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0251</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If case is simplified (additional declaration type B, C, E, F) or supplementary (additional declaration type X, Y, U, V, Z) declaration, then additional information code FIKAT cannot be used.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0252</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If case is special procedure declaration (requested procedure is 44, 46, 48, 51 or 53), then additional information code FIKAT cannot be used.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0253</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>All referenced simplified declarations must be unique.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0262</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF(H5 (both FI &amp; EU) or H7)
THEN
	IF (Additional Procedure code = C08)
	THEN
		Item price must be =&lt; 45 euro
		Importer role must be private person
	ENDIF
ENDIF
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0263</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF (H1 and (Requested procedure = 40)
THEN
	IF (Additional Procedure code = C08)
	THEN
		Item price must be =&lt; 45 euro
		Statistical value must be  =&lt; 45 euro
		Nature of transaction must be 30
		Importer role must be private person
	ENDIF
ENDIF
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0264</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF  (Requested procedure = 61) and case is lodged by private person
THEN
	IF ((H1 and (TARIC code declared)) OR (H5 (both FI &amp; EU) and (Additional Procedure code = B03))
	THEN
		Additional information code must start with "FI" and contains description
		OR Additional document code N830 and export MRN must be declared
	ENDIF
ENDIF
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0265</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF (H1 or H5 (both FI &amp; EU)) and (Requested procedure = 61)
THEN
	IF (((H1 and (TARIC code declared)) OR (H5 (both FI &amp; EU)) and (Additional Procedure code = B02 or 670))
	THEN
		 Additional information code must start with "FI" and contains description 
		OR Additional document code N830 and export MRN must be declared
		
	ENDIF
ENDIF
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0266</Code>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0268</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Postal ID must be unique. For previous document type 781 only PD reference is checked, for type 355 combination reference+transportdocument is checked</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0269</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declaration is lodged retrospectively, additional declaration type must be A.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0270</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If case is postal declaration and is before release, then previous document type 781 cannot be amended and the goods item cannot be removed.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0273</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional information code FIGLO is used, then its description must be one of (1, 3, 6).
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0283</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF additional information code is FIJAE or FISUR, THEN description must be a valid UTU import MRN (second last difgit is R or V).</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0285</Code>
		<DescriptionEn> if requested procedure 42 or 63, then non-FI EU-country, ELSE FI</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0286</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Representation status = 3 (indirect), then Identification number must be the same as in group Declarant.
Not applicable for dataset H5N.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0288</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>FIPRE cannot be used if a quota order number is not entered</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0290</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Either (Amount + Amount currency) or (Quantity + Quantity Unit) must be used, but not both</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0291</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional fiscal reference identification role is FR5, Identification number must be valid IOSS number</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0292</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is 42/63, declared additional fiscal trader reference (role FR1, FR2, FR3 or FR7) must be valid in VIES.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0293</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional procedure code F49 is declared, then importer must be a private person (Role C, P or H).
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0294</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional procedure code F48 and additional fiscal trader reference with role FR5 are declared, then Importer must be a private person (Role C, P or H).
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0295</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional declaration type is C or F and additional information code FIPER is used,
then there cannot exist any manually added liabilities, goods with quota, goods with antidumping or countervailling duties, goods with liability based on proof of origin.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0296</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>For EIDR presentation notification requested procedure must be one of following: 01, 07, 40, 44, 45, 46, 48, 51, 53, 61, 71.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0297</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If amount of calculated duties is higher than 0 (zero), then period must be one week (W). </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0301</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N, Requested procedure is always 40 or 61 and Previous procedure can be 00, 21 or 71.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0302</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N and importer is not VAT registered, VAT code must be declared in this group in correct form (Code FIALK + appropriate Q... code in description)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0303</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If dataset type is H5N and importer is VAT registered, VAT code must be declared in this group in correct form (Code FIALK + appropriate Q... code in description)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0350</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If (submissionTime from serviceOfNotificationDate &gt; 3 years and reason in B, C, I, J, T, X) OR
    (submissionTime from serviceOfNotificationDate &gt; 1 year AND reason in F), then the request will be rejected
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0351</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If request is submitted before the release of goods, amendment type is KOR.
If request is submitted after the release of goods, amendment type is JAL, PAL or OIK.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0353</Code>
		<Description>If original declaration requested procedure in (01, 10, 11, 21, 22, 23, 31, 43, 61, 63, 68, 71, 76, 77, 95, 96) and amended requested procedure is different, change request will be rejected.</Description>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0354</Code>
		<Description>"IF original declaration requestedProcedure in (07, 42, 44, 45, 46, 48, 51, 53) AND amended requestedProcedure is different
THEN 
    IF amended requestedProcedure is not 40
    THEN
            Change request will be rejected
"
</Description>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0355</Code>
		<Description>"IF original declaration requestedProcedure is 40 AND amended requestedProcedure is different,
THEN IF amended requestedProcedure is not in (07, 42, 45, 61)
 
         THEN change request will be rejected
"
</Description>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0357</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested amount is more than 10000€, repayment method cannot be K - cash</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0359</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Target change request cannot be finished or have hearing in progress.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0501</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF requested procedure &lt;&gt;71 and Additional procedure &lt;&gt;615
THEN
Commodity code (a 6-digit HS code or an 8-digit CN code or a 10-digit Taric code) must be valid in Taric on the acceptance date</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0502</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If combined nomenclature code has been declared, harmonised system code must exist as well.
If also Taric code has been declared, both combined nomenclature code and harmonised system code must exist.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0509</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Dataset type is not H2 and  declarant is not VAT Registered, then National additional code Q... must be used</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0510</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Only 1 National additional code Q... can be used</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0511</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>MRN must exist in UTU</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0520</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is FIXBJ, then description must be valid in codelist Customs office of discharge</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0521</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code if FIXBG, then description must be valid in codelist TaloudellisetEdellytys (EconomicCondition)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0522</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is FIXBP, then description must be valid commodity code</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0523</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is FIXBQ, then description must exist in codelist TavaroidenTunnisteTieto  (MethodOfIdentificationOfGoods)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0524</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is FIXBH, then description must be number of months</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR0525</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code if FIPRE, then description must be valid in codelist Preference</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1011</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If authorisation type in [EIR, SDE] AND requested procedure &lt;&gt; 71
THEN 
declared Authorisation/HolderID must be either Importer/IdentificationNumber or Representative/IdentificationNumber</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1012</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF additional declaration type in [Z,V] and authorisation EIR details specify commodity code (5/1), 
THEN each declared commodity code must begin with one of the commodity codes listed in authorisation with as many digits as used in authorisation</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1013</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF additional declaration type in [B,C,E,F,X,Y,U] and authorisation SDE details specify commodity code (5/1), 
THEN each declared commodity code must begin with one of the commodity codes listed in authorisation with as many digits as used in authorisation.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1014</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Additional declaration type is one of (V,Z) and there is no previous eidr notification, then Authorisation must have waiver of the presentation notification</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1109</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Service provider has to be registered as service provider in trader register</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1111</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Trader must be found in Trader register	</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1112</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If submitter is not holder of CW authorisation nor representative in FI434, then he/she must be found trader register and marked there as service provider.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1255</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Quota order number must be valid for Accceptnce date</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1313</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If previous procedure is 71, 
then additional declaration type must be different than 'D', 'E', 'F'.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1314</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF there is at least one Previous document type "IM" 
THEN Additional declaration type D cannot be used</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1315</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If selected type is ”IM”, format must be 17 digits without spaces or any other characters
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1316</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If selected type is ”MRN”, format must be UTU format: 18 characters starting with year and ”FIU” etc.
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1317</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If selected type other value then IM, MRN, ZZZ or 781, format must be generic MRN: 18 characters starting with year and country and then digits and letters and check sum in the end
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1318</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>For declaration types D, E, F only one type of previous declaration types is allowed</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1319</Code>
		<DescriptionEn> ITU can not be precending procedure for D, E, F declarations in UTU. (Previous document type IM)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1320</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Previous document type is IM or MRN, then Previous procedure must be the same as requested procedure on previous document</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1321</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If selected type is ”781”, format must be either Posti - 13 characters: in the beginning and end 2 letters, or Åland post - 11 characters: in the beginning letters AN and in the end letters AX or 21 characters: in the beginning JJFI and 17 numbers. </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1322</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Max length oz ZZZ document is 18 characters</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1323</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If means of transport at the border is mail (5),
then previous document must be of type 781, 355, 821 or ZZZ, 
there must be exactly one repetition of the document with this type on each goods item
and they must have the same reference.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1324</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Previous document must be unique for goods item</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1325</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Previous document must be unique for goods item</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1350</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Post charges cannot be declared both in Additional infrotmation FIALM and Charge type 3A</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1351</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>1A = additions using unclassified amount / 2A = deductions using unclassified amount: cannot be used if amount &gt;= 20 000€ </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1352</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Charge type 6x Tobacco retail price can be used only with AdditionalProcedure C08 </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1353</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>FIALM code is not allowed, should be entered as ChargeType 3A</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1354</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is 07 or 45 and Additional procedure F06 than Goods item Additional infromation code FIXFC must exist</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1355</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is 07 or 45 and Additional procedure F06 then Header Additional information code FIXFA must exist</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1356</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Charge type must be unique for Goods item</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1358</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional info FIKAT exists, then indirect representative or direct FITAK representative cannot be used.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1375</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code if FICOM, then description must be valid commodity code</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1376</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Unfinished Invalidation request initiated by trader must exist</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1379</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If reason code is K, declarant must be private person</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1380</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If reason code is N, target declaration type must be D</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1381</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is FIARE then Additional information code FISUR must exist</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1382</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is FISUR then Additional Declaration type must be A</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1383</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Replacing MRN must exist in UTU</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1384</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If (additional declaration type is R or additional information code is FISUR) and requested procedure is 44, 46, 48, 51 or 53 then authorization type must be EUS, OPO, IPO or TEA</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1390</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional declaration type is not A, B or C then additional information FIFAL is not allowed.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1391</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional information code is FIFAL then Description must be valid date </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR1392</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If declarant is private person, FIFAL-code is not allowed. </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR2001</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Representative is used,
then authorization holder must not be the same as Representative,</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR2003</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Submiter ID must be the same as for declarant, representative or service provider in the original/amended declaration.
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR2007</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Unfinished change request or not correct state of declaration</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR2010</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Time limit extension is not possible for Time limit type</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR2011</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Time limit T2 cannot be extended,  if case is waiting for supplementary declaration</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR2012</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Time limit T3 cannot be extended, if requested procedure in case details is 46, 48 or 53.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR2020</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Time limit does not exist</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3001</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If exists additional procedure code 150, then there must be declared additional document of type C601 in the corresponding goods item.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3002</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is different than 71,
previous procedure is 21,
and declaration is not lodged from TUTTU,
then there must exist either:
- additional document type C019, or
- additional information code FISAP.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3003</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If previous procedure is either 11 or 21
and declaration is not lodged from TUTTU,
then there must be declared either:
- additional document type C660,
- additional document type C710, or
- additional information code FIOEI.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3004</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is 51 and previous procedure is 21, 
then nature of transaction must be 41, 42, or 60.

Else if requested procedure is other than 51 or 71, and previous procedure is 21, then nature of transaction must be 21, 22, 51, 52 or 60."
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3005</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is different than 71 and
previous procedure is 21,
then preference (4/17) must be 100.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3006</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional procedure B02 is declared and
declaration is not lodged from TUTTU,
then there must be declared additional information code FITAC on corresponding goods item.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3007</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional information code 00800 is declared, then there also must exist additional information code 00700.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3008</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100, then Additional Declaration type must be A or D.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3009</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional information code is FIPRE,
then previous procedure must be 21 and
requested procedure must be either 61, 63 or 68.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3010</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional information codes 00100 (header level) and FIARE (item level) are declared,
then Importer must be finnish or EU private person (C, H).</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3011</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional procedure code 204 or 205 is declared,
then export country must exist in codelist Codelist;UnderAgreementForPreference.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3012</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional procedure code 204 or 205 is used, then
nature of transaction (8/5) must be 60 and
preference (4/17) must be 100.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3013</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If additional procedure code 204 or 205 is used, then
additional information code FIUKV must exist on corresponding goods item.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3014</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If previous procedure is 51 and
additional procedure code 160 is declared,
then additional document type C601 must exist on the corresponding goods item.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3015</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If previous procedure is 53 and
additional procedure code 160 is declared,
then additional document type C516 must exist on the corresponding goods item.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3016</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If previous procedure is 71 and
additional procedure code 160 is declared,
then there must exist additional document of type either C517, C518 or C519 on corresponding goods item.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3017</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If requested procedure is 61, 63 or 68,
previous procedure is 21 and
additional procedure code 160 is declared,
then additional document type C019 must exist on the corresponding goods item.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3018</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested procedure = 44 THEN
    one of the following must be declared:
    - Authorisation type EUS
    - Additional information code 00100 (header-level)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3019</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested procedure = 44 THEN Nature of transaction must be in [11, 60, 91]</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3020</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested procedure = 44 THEN Preference must be in [100, 120, 200, 220, 300, 320]</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3021</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requested procedure is 44 and additional procedure 653 exists, then Additional information code FIALV must be declared</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3022</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested Procedure = 46 THEN Authorisation type OPO must exist</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3023</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested procedure = 46 THEN Nature of transaction must be in [51, 52]</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3024</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested procedure = 48 THEN
    one of the following must be declared:
    - Authorisation type OPO
    - Additional information code 00100 (header-level)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3025</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested procedure = 48 THEN Nature of transaction must be in [60]</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3026</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested Procedure = 51 THEN
    IF Previous procedure = 11 THEN
        Authorisation type IPO must exists
    ELSE
        one of the following must be declared:
        - Authorisation type IPO
        - Additional information code 00100 (header)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3027</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested procedure = 51 THEN  Nature of transaction must be in [11, 41, 42, 60]</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3028</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested procedure = 51 AND Previous procedure = 11 THEN
there must exist Previous document type 830 (with export MRN) and
either additional document type C710 or additional information code FIOEI.
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3030</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requested procedure is 51 and Previous procedure is 21 THEN
o only one previous document (IM and ID for import declaration which was lodged for placing goods under original procedure 51) may exist under additional documents
AND
o only one previous document for temporary re-export for futher processing (MRN and ID for export declaration) may exist in additional documents</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3035</Code>
		<DescriptionEn> If Requested Procedure is 53 then Authorisation Type TEA must exist or Additional information code 00100 must exist.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3036</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requested procedure is 53 then Nature of transaction must be 60 </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3037</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requested procedure is 53 then Additional procedure must be Dxx for each goods item</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3038</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requested procedure is 53 then Additional procedure must always be the same for each goods item</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3041</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requested procedure is 44,46,48,51 or 53 then there must be ONE of the following Previous documents for each goods item:
 o type 337 and temporary storage declaration MRN (in AREX) 
 o  type 355 and entry summary declaration MRN (in AREX)
 o type 820, 821 or 952, and transit MRN
 o type ZZZ and reference to customs warehousing SAD or free text (form 613 etc)
 o type MRN and customs warehousing MRN or import declaration (in UTU) 
 o type IM (national previous document) and case identification number (MRN)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3050</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Additional information code 00100 can be used only if Authorisation IPO, OPO, EUS or TEA is not declared</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3060</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Previous procedure = 11
THEN Authorization type IPO must include Prior export of products obtained from equivalent goods</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3061</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Previous procedure is 51 there must be declared one of the following previous documents for each goods item:
o type 'IM' (national previous document type) and case identification number (MRN) of inward processing declaration
o type MRN and case identification number (MRN) of inward processing declaration
o type 821 and transit MRN?? &lt; tarkista!
or 
o Additional document type C710(detail of used  the standardized exchange of information exists</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3062</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Previous Procedure is 54 then either Additional document type = C610 (INF9) or Additional information code = FIOEI must excist</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3068</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional procedure code is D02 then Period of discharge (FIXBH) must be 1-12 months</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3069</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional procedure code is D08 then Period of discharge (FIXBH) must be 12-24 months</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3070</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional procedure code in [D20, D22, D24] then Period of discharge (FIXBH) must be 1-6 months</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3073</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional procedure code is D28 then Period of discharge (FIXBH) must be 1-3 months</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3077</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If  Additional document type is C601 then Authorisation register must return authorisation type IPO</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3078</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If  Authorisation type is  one of the following: (IPO, EUS, TEA) then
Authorization holder ID and the Identification number of the declarant must be the same, except in case:
o Requested procedure is 51 and Previous procedure is 11 and Additional document type is C710 (INF IP EX/IM) 
or Additional information code = FIOEI (then Authorization holder id and the identification number of the declarant need not to be the same).</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3079</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If  Additional document type is C990 or N990 AND additional information code  00100 does not exist then
authorisation type must be EUS.
</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3080</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If  Additional document type is C516 
THEN Authorisation register must return authorisation type TEA</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3082</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Authorisation type is OPO and Requested procedure is 48 then authorisation must include Prior import of replacement products</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3085</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and  requested procedure is either 44,48,51  or 53 then Period for  discharge of the procedure is mandatory  (FIXBH) </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3087</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and  Requested procedure is one of the following: 44 , 48, 51, or 53 then Customs office(s) of discharge is mandatory (FIXBJ) </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3088</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and  Requested procedure is one of the following: 44, 48, 51, or 53 then Place(s) of processing or use is mandatory (FIXAC) </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3091</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and  Requested procedure is either 44, 48 or 51 then Rate of yield is mandatory (FIXBO) </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3092</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and  Requested procedure is one of the following: 44 ,48, 51, or 53 then Identification of goods is mandatory (FIXBQ) </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3093</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and  Requested procedure is one of the following: 44, 48, 51, or 53 then Details of planned activities is mandatory (FIXBN) </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3094</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and  requested procedure is one of the following: 44 , 51 then First place of use or processing is optional if Declarant ID EORI is Finnish or other EU otherwise mandatory  (FIFPU)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3097</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and requested procedure is 44,48 or 51 then At least one CN code of Processed products is mandatory (FIXBP) </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3098</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and Additional information code FIXBP exists  then Free description of Processed products is mandatory (FIXBB) </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3099</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and Requested procedure is 51 then at least one of the Economic conditions is mandatory (FIXBG)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3100</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF authorisation type is EUS AND Authorisation Register returned national code 89A in commodity code data (5/1) THEN footnote EU003 must exist for each goods item</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3101</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF authorisation type is EUS AND Authorisation Register returned national code 88B in commodity code data (5/1) THEN measure footnote EU001 must exist for each goods item</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3103</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and Requested procedure is 53 then 
o Owner of the goods is mandatory in cases when Additional procedure code is one of the following: D03, D08, D09, D12, D13, D16, D17, or D24. (FIOOG)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3105</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information type is 00100 and Requested procedure is 51 then
o Previous procedure 21 is not allowed for any goods item</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3106</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Additional information code is 00100 and Requested procedure is 51 then either UCC 85 art (FID85)  or 86(3) art (FID86)  of the Code must be declared for the calculation of the amount of the import duty</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3107</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Requested procedure in [44, 46, 48, 51, 53] THEN  Representation status must be 2</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3118</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requested procedure is 51 and Previous procedure is  other than 11 and authorisation type is IPO
THEN UTU checks automatically in Authorisation register: TARIC code (6/15) in the customs declaration must match with the first 4 digits (CN-level) to one of the codes (data element 5/1) included in the authorisation.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3119</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If authorisation type is IPO, OPO, EUS or TEA THEN authorisation must be valid in authorisation register UTU checks automatically in Authorisation register: Start date of the decision (4/6) and Date of expiry of the decision (4/7) in authorisation details. IF previous procedure is 11 or 21 THEN autorisation does not need to be valid</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3122</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requested procedure is 44 and Authorisation type is EUS UTU checks automatically in  Authorisation register: TARIC code (5/1) in the customs declaration must match with the 10 digits (CN-level) in the authorisation(data element 5/1)</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3123</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requested procedure is 53 Period of discharge (FIXBH) Maximum value is 24</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3124</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>If Requested procedure is 44 or 51 Period of discharge (FIXBH) Maximum value is 36</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>NR3125</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>IF Additional information code in [FIXBJ, FIXBO, FID85, FID86, FIXBG, FIXBN, FIXBP, FIXBQ, FIXIG, FIXAC, FIFPU, FIOOG, FISPI, FIXBH] THEN Additional information code 00100 must exist</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>R0005</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>When submitting a new declaration or amendment before release, goods Item Number’ is always used even if ‘Items’ = ‘1’, ‘Goods Item Number’ is also ‘1’. </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>R0007</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Each ‘Goods Item Number’ is unique throughout the declaration. When submitting a new declaration or amendment before release, the items shall be numbered in a sequential fashion, starting from '1' for the first item and incrementing the numbering by '1' for each following item". </DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>R0285</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>When a detail is common to all goods items, it must be declared at declaration header level. The details are declared at goods item level only if they differ from each other.</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>R0671</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>This information is to be provided where the buyer is different to the person provided in D.E. 3/15 Importer</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>R0672</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>This information is to be provided where the seller is different to the person provided in D.E. 3/1 Exporter</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
	<RC>
		<Code>R0862</Code>
		<DescriptionEn>Declarant ID cannot be amended	</DescriptionEn>
	</RC>
</RulesCondition>