<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSpy v2018 (x64) (http://www.altova.com) by Finnish Customs (Finnish Customs) -->
<MessageExchange xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../MessageExchange.xsd">
	<Intro>
		<TextLine lang="fi">Tässä sanomaliikenneoppaassa on kuvattu sanomaliikenne Tullilta väliaikaisen varaston luvanhaltijalle, kun henkilöasiakas on tehnyt tuonti-ilmoituksen Tullin asiointipalvelussa UTU-järjestelmään. Varaston luovutussanoma voidaan lähettää väliaikaisen varaston luvanhaltijalle, kun ilmoituksella on tavaran sijaintipaikaksi ilmoitettu väliaikainen varasto ja luvanhaltija käyttää sanoma-asiointia. </TextLine>
		<TextLine lang="sv">I denna guide för meddelandetrafik beskrivs meddelandetrafiken från Tullen till innehavaren av tillstånd till tillfälligt lager, när en personkund har ingett en importdeklaration till UTU-systemet via Tullens e-tjänst. Meddelandet om frigörande från lager kan skickas till innehavaren av tillstånd till tillfälligt lager, när man i deklarationen har angett tillfälligt lager som varans förvaringsplats och tillståndshavaren använder meddelandedeklarering.</TextLine>
		<TextLine lang="en">This guide for message exchange includes the description of the message exchange from Customs to the holder of the temporary storage authorisation, when a private person has submitted an import declaration in Customs’ online service to the UTU system. The storage release notification can be sent to the holder of the temporary storage authorisation, when the temporary storage facility has been declared as the location of goods in the declaration and the authorisation holder uses message exchange. </TextLine>
	</Intro>
	<Messages>
		<Message>
			<Sender>Customs</Sender>
			<ID>FI419</ID>
			<Name lang="fi">Varaston luovutussanoma</Name>
			<Name lang="sv">Meddelande om frigörande från lager</Name>
			<Name lang="en">Storage release notification</Name>
			<DescriptionLine lang="fi">Tulli ilmoittaa, että tavarat voi luovuttaa tavaran noutajalle / kuljettaa vastaanottajalle.</DescriptionLine>
			<DescriptionLine lang="sv">Tullen meddelar att varorna kan lämnas över till hämtaren / transporteras till mottagaren.</DescriptionLine>
			<DescriptionLine lang="en">Customs notifies that the goods can be handed over to the person picking them up / transported to the consignee.</DescriptionLine>
		</Message>
	</Messages>
	<UseCases>
		<UseCase>
			<Name lang="fi">Varaston luovutussanoma</Name>
			<Name lang="sv">Meddelande om frigörande från lager</Name>
			<Name lang="en">Storage release notification</Name>
			<Sequence>
				<Customs>FI419</Customs>
			</Sequence>
			<SequenceDescription>
				<Item>
					<ItemLine lang="fi">Tulli lähettää väliaikaisen varaston luvanhaltijalle varaston luovutussanoman (FI419).</ItemLine>
					<ItemLine lang="sv">Tullen skickar ett meddelande om frigörande från lager (FI419) till innehavaren av lagertillståndet genom direkt meddelandedeklarering.</ItemLine>
					<ItemLine lang="en">Customs sends the storage release notification (FI419) to the holder of the temporary storage authorisation via direct message exchange.</ItemLine>
					<ItemLine lang="fi">Tällä sanomalla Tulli ilmoittaa, että tavarat on tulliselvitetty eli luovutettu tullimenettelyyn, eikä Tullin puolesta ole estettä luovuttaa tavaraa eteenpäin.</ItemLine>
					<ItemLine lang="sv">Med detta meddelande delges kunden att varorna har tullklarerats, dvs. frigjorts för ett tullförfarande, och att det för Tullens del inte förekommer hinder för att överlåta varorna vidare.</ItemLine>
					<ItemLine lang="en">With this notification, Customs notifies that the goods have been cleared through customs, that is, they have been released for a customs procedure and, as far as Customs is concerned, the goods can be released from temporary storage.</ItemLine>
					<ItemLine lang="fi">Tullin järjestelmä tarkastaa tulli-ilmoitussanomalla ilmoitetun varaston tunnuksen perusteella, voiko varastoluvan haltija ottaa sanomamuotoisen tiedon varastosta luovutuksesta vastaan. Jos voi, Tullin järjestelmä lähettää luovutussanoman asiakkaalle.</ItemLine>
					<ItemLine lang="sv">Tullens system kontrollerar utifrån lagerkoden som angetts i tulldeklarationsmeddelandet huruvida innehavaren av lagertillståndet kan ta emot uppgiften om frigörande från lager i meddelandeform. Om svaret är ja, skickar Tullens system ett meddelande om frigörande till kunden.</ItemLine>
					<ItemLine lang="en">On the basis of the warehouse ID declared in the customs declaration message, Customs’ system checks if the holder of the temporary storage authorisation can receive the notification of release from storage in message format. If yes, Customs’ system will send the release notification to the customer.</ItemLine>
				</Item>
			</SequenceDescription>
		</UseCase>
	</UseCases>
</MessageExchange>
